SUMMARY

Professional software engineer with some experience participating in the complete product development lifecycle of successfully launched applications. Also an enthusiastic, a problem solver and person who can work well as an individual or in a group.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Faculty of Computer Science University of Indonesia



MUHAMMAD HASBY ROSYADI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

January 2022 - Presents

PT. Sejahtera Lunaria Annua (KoinWorks)

- Build Rest API for Investment (KoinP2P and KoinRobo) use Go Language
- Build and use gRPC for consume data
- Integrated Shopee Payment for KoinRobo transaction
- Refactor transaction KoinRobo for thirdparty payment
- Translate Product Requirement Document (PRD) to System Design
- Maintainable Service Backoffice
- Created New Product RoboFlexi for KoinRobo
- Created Feature Blacklist User (Internal)
- Created Feature Forgot Password for Backoffice (Internal)
- Created Feature Anti Money Laundry (AML) (Internal)
- Created Unit Test and Designed Database System

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

February 2021 - January 2022

PT. Prudential Life Assurance

- Build Rest API for PruMedical Network with Java Language
- Revamp Document Service in Individual with Vert. X Framework
- Create Feature Document Service with E-Doc tools from regional
- Developed Feature Interim Bill for Guarantee Of Payment
- Adjust and Enhance Feature existing like GOP PruCermat, Revise LOG, refactor feature cause founded by Audit, fixing bugs in Prod
- Breakdown Task from User Story and Assign to Developer

CERTIFICATION

Information Systems Management / Information Technology Specialization

SOCIAL

- ₽ Linkedin.com/in/hasbyrosyadi
- & (+62) 8235 7802 930
- P hasbyrosyadi1995@gmail.com

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Java

SQL

Golang

HTML/CSS

Tools & Frameworks:

Github

DataDog

Docker

Kubernetes

Bitbucket

MySQL

PostgreSQL

gRPC

Springboot Framework

Apache Flink

Vert. X Framework

Couchbase (NoSQL)

Kafka

Jira

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

February 2019 - February 2021

PT. Tamasia Global Sharia

- Build Rest API for Tamasia Apps with Golang Language
- Revamp Registration Flow Tamasia Apps
- Created Unit Test and Designed Database System
- Developed System Payment with Giropos and ShopeePay
- Adjust Printed Gold Series Antam and Dinar
- Develop API for Redeem Voucher with Barcode and Dormant Fee
- Review Code before Staging

WEB DEVELOPER

April 2018 - February 2019

PUSILKOM Universitas Indonesia

- Developed Portal Sistem Informasi KPU.
- Created and designed analyst system
- Developed Plagiat Checker system

AWARD

Competition: 2nd Winner of Web Design at Himpunan Mahasiswa Sistem Informasi Bina Nusantara

PROJECT

Sistem Informasi Akademik Future Generation (SIAK-FG): Web Developer